The song you know. The story you don't.
I Can Only Imagine is a music, drama film directed by Andrew Erwin.
Growing up in Greenville, Texas, Bart Millard suffers physical and
emotional abuse at the hands of his father, Arthur.
When Arthur becomes terminally ill, he finds redemption by embracing
his faith and rediscovering his love for his son.
Years later, Bart's troubled childhood and mended relationship with his dad inspires him to
write the hit song "I Can Only Imagine" as singer of the Christian band MercyMe.
Bart Millard, played by J. Michael Finley.
Arthur, played by Dennis Quaid.
Memaw, played by Cloris Leachman.
Young Bart, played by Brody Rose.
Shannon, played by Madeline Carroll.
Dr. Avondale, played by Gianna Simone.
I Can Only Imagine is a 2018 American Christian biographical drama film directed by the Erwin Brothers and written by Alex Cramer, Jon Erwin, and
Brent McCorkle, based on the story behind the group MercyMe's song of the same name, the best-selling Christian single of all time.
The film stars J.
Michael Finley as Bart Millard, the lead singer who wrote the song
about his relationship with his father (Dennis Quaid).
Madeline Carroll, Trace Adkins, Priscilla Shirer, and Cloris Leachman also star.
I Can Only Imagine was released in the United States on March 16, 2018.
It was a box office success, grossing $86 million worldwide against a production
budget of $7 million, earning more than twelve times its budget.
It is the fifth highest-grossing music biopic and sixth
highest-grossing Christian film of all-time in the United States.
Some critics praised it as inspiring and noted it as an improvement compared to other
faith-based films, while others called it flat and by-the-numbers.
At the 2018 Dove Awards, the film won "Inspirational Film of the Year".
The film explores themes of musician, texas, abusive
father, redemption, based on true story.
The tone is emotional.